<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-10-14T11:44:23+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Aayusha Writes</title><subtitle>Writing and making memories.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Chicken Shwarma in Kathmandu</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Best-Shwarma-In-Kathmandu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chicken Shwarma in Kathmandu" /><published>2019-09-17T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-09-17T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Best-Shwarma-In-Kathmandu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Best-Shwarma-In-Kathmandu/">&lt;p&gt;It’s actually been a month or two where I have indulged myself into blogging and I realize that I love to write. Just not write 
but to express every single thing that outstands me, be it the foods, travel, my perspectives or the recipes I try to cook.
It simply feels good to connect with my readers through my writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And ever since I have started blogging, every single thing I do makes me do it “bloggable”. Therefore, this time I decided
to go hunt the famous middle east food called the &lt;mark class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;'shwarma roll'&lt;/mark&gt; in the alleys of Thamel. My love for rolls initially started with 
a huge influence from someone I heart very much. He is basically heads over heels for rolls and my quest of surprising him 
with a unique middle east flavour bought me to the place called Thamel Doner Kebab. The last I remember, they have amazing 
variety of stuffs you can make a roll out of which includes the doner kebab obviously, shwarma rolls and falafel rolls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several take away shops in Kathmandu that offers you rolls but then we do not have any authentic Nepali rolls with Nepali
favours. It’s either the Calcutta’s famous katti rolls or the rolls of Syanko. And to be honest, wraps are famous all over the 
world, specially the wraps of Arab Cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had been informed about this place recently by a food vlogger who had visited to try the authentic shwarma and falafel rolls in Kathmandu
at Thamel and we were extremely intimidated by the way she portrayed the food. You also would want to eat it if you watch the video.
And that is how a friend of mine and I decided to kick our scooters off to that place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Where is it exactly?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest we also had a tough time finding the place merely because both of us do not carry a smartphone and were unable to
find the place through maps. The only thing we knew was that it’s right beside Kathmandu Grand Hotel. And hence, we called 
a friend of ours to find us the exact location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For you people who has smartphone however can just google the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Thamel+Doner+Kebab/@27.7175251,85.3083662,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb18e33066c6f1:0x6eebff496238d965!8m2!3d27.7174402!4d85.3102514&quot;&gt;location&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you get to Thamel, head straight to Kalapathar. On kalapathar, you’ll find a junction that goes either left or right.
The road we should be taking is the right one. Head straight for about five minutes and keep on mind the “hotel’s name” (that’s
what we did). Once you find the Kathmandu Grand Hotel, the doner kebab shop is right beside it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;What did we order?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu there was a page long with so many items we had never heard our entire life, but we did knew that pieces of meat
and fats were stacked over a rod which was slowly cooked in a circular motion with consistent heat coming from a heater and it was
called the shwarma meat. Veggies, cheese, shwarma meat and their authentic sauce was kept in a flat bread and rolled to form
a shwarma roll. And that is what we ordered. Any one who would want their roll to be gluten free could also order flat bread made
up of wheat. The roll is slightly grilled to give the smokey flavour. Served with chilly sauce, normal tomato ketchup and veggies
dipped in vinegar, I genuinely felt that this one is probably the finest shwarma roll we can find in Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I surely recommend you to visit the place and try their shwarma at least once. It might not be your go to place when you’re hungry
but it obviously would be a dish you would not regret trying on.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">It’s actually been a month or two where I have indulged myself into blogging and I realize that I love to write. Just not write but to express every single thing that outstands me, be it the foods, travel, my perspectives or the recipes I try to cook. It simply feels good to connect with my readers through my writing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/swarmaroll.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Twenty Hours of Blockchain | With eSatya</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Twenty-Hours-of-Blockchain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Twenty Hours of Blockchain | With eSatya " /><published>2019-09-08T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-09-08T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Twenty-Hours-of-Blockchain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Twenty-Hours-of-Blockchain/">&lt;p&gt;Every year our college introduces a series of workshops related to information technology. These workshops are made available to students so that they can learn something that is fresh in the real world and can help them get a head start in a particular field. With all the heated stories regarding crypto-currency, bitcoin, smart contract, and whatnot, I always wanted to know what is the real deal regarding blockchain technology? What makes it different and revolutionary? So, I decided to seize this opportunity and choose Blockchain without giving a second thought. Little did I know, I would be so fascinated about it that I would want to share my 20 hours journey with blockchain, to my dear readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike other technology, blockchain is relatively new and there are not many people who have been engaging in this technology. So, it must have been a great challenge for the administrative department to find the instructors suitable to teach the course. Nevertheless, they found cool developers who devoted themselves to Blockchain in Nepal. They were the blockchain geeks and worked in a company named eSatya.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjik dai and Ruchin dai instructed us in the very first class. They were very enthusiastic and proactive. One could see their passion for the technology just by glancing at their t-shirt with the print “Blockchain Guy”. They seemed to be very excited to find people sharing common interest concerning Blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first class was not directly about setting up the coding environment. It was about understanding why we were in that class and what we were about to learn. Further, the class also came up into clear understanding on what eSatya does for Nepal in the context of Blockchain. The class gradually became more interactive while discussing the stupidest curious stuff one could have. Afterward, we had a short presentation given by our instructors and the very first class ended with the installation of all the required materials to dig into the blockchain for the future lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 20 hours of Blockchain was divided into five Saturdays, each of four hours. I would like to describe the first lesson as exhilarating the second lesson was not monotonous either, but we could fairly say who wanted to learn the subject in an indulging fashion and who felt like an obligation to make up for their attendance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as we knew, blockchain was used for the transaction of digital crypto-currency. The next step was to understand every single element that made transaction possible in any system that blockchain encapsulates. The small concept like hash, block, tokens, nonce, proof of work, were discussed with interactive examples. Later we learned how blockchain is a distributed system and has the power to replace the traditional centralized system. The second class was also about understanding the status of blockchain in Nepal, especially when bitcoin is illegal here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next four hours of the third week was the turning point. It was now finally the time to get our hands dirty and start coding and write contracts. We’d been hearing about contracts for the last two classes so much that there was an immense urge to kill our curiosity and know more about it in a technical way. When finally getting into it, we were introduced to Solidity; Solidity is an object-oriented programming language for writing smart contracts. Solidity was a challenge itself. We had to have good knowledge about javascript, but then learning a different programming language was a bite off more than we could chew. But we did it anyway, with the help of our instructors who pushed us beyond our limits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Manjik dai told us to think about a project which could be anything where blockchain could be implemented. Once we decide our project, we could then start the project-based learning. Groups were divided and after a few minutes of brainstorming, we had a project idea ready. We decided to do a tax payment system and we were asked to pitch our idea formally into documents. Everything felt rushed at the moment because the only time we invested ourselves in this was in the Saturday classes. Having said that we would deliver a pitch anyways, exams awaited us the coming week. It was next to impossible to manage time for both the exams and project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After exams, we had three sleepless nights to deliver what we had thought to design. Despite the fact that not all promised details were made exactly the same, we felt victorious when we had something to show in front of everyone. Our mentors were very happy for us for trying something we had never done before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cut a long story short, Blockchain classes felt like an achievement at the end. I am very happy to have mentors who are either a text or call away from help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel like knowing more about eSatya and blockchain itself then you can contact me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Aayusha2055/blockchain-tax&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the link to the project we had made.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Technology" /><category term="Journal" /><category term="SelfThoughts" /><category term="Blockchain" /><category term="eSatya" /><category term="Power Workshop" /><category term="Self Improvement" /><category term="Extrovert" /><category term="Thisweek" /><summary type="html">Every year our college introduces a series of workshops related to information technology. These workshops are made available to students so that they can learn something that is fresh in the real world and can help them get a head start in a particular field. With all the heated stories regarding crypto-currency, bitcoin, smart contract, and whatnot, I always wanted to know what is the real deal regarding blockchain technology? What makes it different and revolutionary? So, I decided to seize this opportunity and choose Blockchain without giving a second thought. Little did I know, I would be so fascinated about it that I would want to share my 20 hours journey with blockchain, to my dear readers.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/esatya_bk.png" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Gajar Ko Haluwa | Home Cooking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Gajar-Ko-Haluwa/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Gajar Ko Haluwa | Home Cooking" /><published>2019-09-06T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-09-06T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Gajar-Ko-Haluwa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Gajar-Ko-Haluwa/">&lt;p&gt;This gajar ko haluwa is a dessert made with lots of carrot and lots of milk and a quite bit of sugar and it’s absolutely 
amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me when I say this, you are sure to have extreme sugar cravings during the weight loss phase. I have been there and had it 
and understood how difficult it is to cope up with it and what choices we make for our sweet tooth. On this phase, one thing
I always wondered was how to utilize low calorie foods for dealing with such stuffs. And then the internet that suggests you to
eat fruits and greek yogurts and dark chocolates but that’s pretty much something that you do not want to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter was my inspiration of creating the gajar ko haluwa in true Nepalish way. I think they’re amazing and a nice alternative
to our sweet tooth. Beautiful both inside out, tasty and not hard to make at all, I have outlined the detailed steps in the
tutorial that follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure to try this out and have fun while cooking!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;recipe-contents&quot;&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ul&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 kgs of Carrot&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 litre milk&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 large tablespoon of ghee &lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;50gms of Oarsman (Khuwa) &lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Half tablespoon cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;100ml condensed milk&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;5 tablespoon of sugar&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;12-15 cardamons&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
          
 &lt;div class=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ol&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Wash the carrot properly and peel them. Once you do it grate it nice and small.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Heat a pan and add the ghee in it. Once the ghee starts getting hot, add the grated carrot into it.
       Once the carrot starts heating, it releases the juice in it. We need to cook the carrot completely, until it sucks 
       all of its water.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Another alternative to doing the previous step would be to cook the carrots in the pressure cooker
        until two full hissing sound. Once it's done you can then add the carrots into the pan and fry it with ghee. This
        way you'll get your work done a lot faster.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Pour one whole litre of milk in the carrots. Take another pan and melt the khuwa. Also add the melted khuwa in the
       mixture.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;If you like chewing cardamons then you might not want to powder it. But I personally would suggest you to add 
       5 pieces as it is and the rest of them to be made into powder and add them.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Add sugar and cinnamon powder into the mixture and cook it in small flame till you see that the milk level has 
       risen down and started to get thicker.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Garnish with any dry fruits you love and enjoy the haluwa warm or cool down further to eat it as a dessert.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you did try making this at home, drop a comment below and share about how it ended up.
 And would also love to hear you’re horror cooking stories. You tell yours and i’ll tell you mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="Guide" /><category term="Homecook" /><category term="Homecooking" /><category term="Pudding" /><category term="HealthyFood" /><category term="NepaliFood" /><summary type="html">This gajar ko haluwa is a dessert made with lots of carrot and lots of milk and a quite bit of sugar and it’s absolutely amazing.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/gajarkohaluwa.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Air Frying Chicken | Home Cooking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Air-Fryer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Air Frying Chicken | Home Cooking" /><published>2019-08-25T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-25T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Air-Fryer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Air-Fryer/">&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, things turn out great without oil as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Past two months of my life has turned complete upside down as I had a sudden urge to loose weight. Things would have been 
pretty normal if I was slightly overweight but I was obese for my height and age. I stand about 4.11 from the ground and 
would weight almost 132.2 where according to the calculations, I should be no more than 112.4lbs. That’s when getting in shape
became important to me. I joined the gym, started working out about two hours a day and ate in calorie deficit. I repeated the same
pattern of foods for breakfast, lunch and dinner. On most of the days, I would even avoid dinners. Following the same boring food pattern
was difficult and I would crave for things I used to hate. I wanted to eat amazing chicken, deep fried momos with hot sauce,
and all those things that would not allow me to loose weight. For your information, Nepali cuisines need a lot of oil as well.
That’s where things get rough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right at this time, my uncle came with Air Fryer to visit us. He brought it from China and wanted us to try it out. Initially,
I had no idea what it would do but later I can state that it “changed my life”. I’ve prepared hundreds of food and the same food
hundred times and I eat them all guilt free. Getting in shape has turned my mindset into counting calories and air fryer
has successfully been able to remove that extra 110 calories from my plate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve got a air fryer too then why not indulge in my recipes then. This time I will be writing about making delicious 
soft and tender chicken with air fryer. If you want it to be extremely juicy you can add the oil. As far as I do this, I
avoid the oil. In Nepal, the completely dried meat is also called chicken sekuwa. Let’s get started then!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chicken with bones (1 kgs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Curd (One small cup)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Salt (1 and half teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turmeric (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Red Chilly Powder (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nepali Chilly (Akabare) Paste (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jeera Seed (Half teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carom Seed (Half teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2-3 Cardamons&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Coriander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two Onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half a garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Half a ginger&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Equipments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air Fryer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blender&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saucepan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bowl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chop the onion into small pieces and keep then inside the air fryer for about 5 minutes in 180 degree. While 
the onion keeps on getting caramelized, heat a saucepan to roast cardamons, jeera seed and carom seed. You can roast them
for about 2 to 3 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When both the onions and the seeds are done, turn them into the blender. Slice the ginger and garlic into small pieces 
and add them into the blender. Add mint, coriander, salt, turmeric, chilly powder, paste and curd into the blender and blend t
all of these ingredients into a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the chicken into a big bowl and add the paste to it. Mix it well and leave the chicken for minimum two hours. I
generally like to marinate my meat overnight, but you can do it as much as you like.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you start being impatient about the chicken that’s when you’ll know it’s ready to get inside the fryer. Gently place
the chicken into the fryer. Do not overload. Add only if the counter space is free.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can do it first for 5 minutes in about 180 to 190 degree. Come back, shake it well, turn the pieces upside down
and keep it back again for another 5 minutes. Voila! You’ll get somewhat grilled and somewhat fried chicken two in one at
the same time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Things to be Cautious About&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Chicken&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of air frying recipes of chicken would want you to cook it without marination but this Nepali style chicken goes completely
fine inside the air fryer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Keep Shaking it like a boss&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaking the fryer would allow everything inside it to move and allow the hot air to circulate to every surface of each food.
I recommend you do it more often like in between every five minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Do not overload&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As small as the counter is, that’s how small portion we should be keeping inside it. You would definitely not be staking foods
one after another in your usual pan or even in the over and that goes same with the fryer.
Fryers do come with racks these days, but you shouldn’t overload it anyways. This is also because frying means cooking the food
equally from all the parts. That is why you need to leave enough room for food to cook in the fryer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;A note from the author&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/chicken-air-fryed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="Guide" /><category term="Airfryer" /><category term="Home Cooking" /><category term="Healthy Food" /><category term="Leanin15" /><category term="NepaliFood" /><summary type="html">Interestingly, things turn out great without oil as well.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/airfryer.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kheer, Nepali Rice Pudding | Home Cooking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Rice-Pudding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kheer, Nepali Rice Pudding | Home Cooking" /><published>2019-08-24T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-24T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Rice-Pudding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Rice-Pudding/">&lt;p&gt;THE ULTIMATE CROWN OF NEPALI CUISINE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty obvious to love your county’s cuisine despite the fact that foreign cuisine seems tempting af. My country is known for
the variety of culture and people, it’s beauty, mountains, wildlife and lakes and so much more but people might rarely say
any names if you ask them about our cuisine. They might have a few names to say, but you would definitely not hear about kheer.
And who would make the best out of all Nepali cuisines except for the locals that eat them regularly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as I know, kheer was discovered by farmers, who would be eating it to celebrate successful harvest. This totally sweet and
delicious dish took only a short period of time to get it’s place on every Nepalis heart. It’s usually eaten in the month of June and July
where the farmers harvest the rice and entire Nepalese home makes Kheer to celebrate. But that’s not only the custom we have here. 
To mark successful harvest in this period, this sweet rice pudding, is made as a Prasad in the name of god and eat it themselves. 
And today, it has been a custom to definitely cook this at least once in the month of June and July to respect the entire farmer family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish particularly isn’t a difficult one to make but does requires a lot of patience and love. Your’e basically at
the right spot to find out what it takes to make one delicious bowl of Kheer. Hope you gather 
all the ingredients as soon as possible into your kitchen, indulge into it and treat your loved ones with its.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;recipe-contents&quot;&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ul&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 litre milk&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;A cup of rice&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;50gms sugar&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Dry fruits - Raisins and Almonds&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;10 Cardamons seeds&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
          
 &lt;div class=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ol&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Soak the rice in water for about 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Keep the milk into boil. Completely drain the water from the rice and pour it into boiling milk.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Keep stirring the rice for about 15 to 20 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;You can add pepper and cardamon as much as you feel like into the rice and milk mixture. As you keep on cooking the rice, you will
       notice that the milk starts to thicken and the rice starts to cook.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Pour the sugar and dry fruits into the mixture and cook it further for 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Garnish with almonds and enjoy the warm pudding or cool down further to eat it as a dessert.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you did try making this at home, drop a comment below and share about how it ended up.
 And would also love to hear you’re horror cooking stories. You tell yours and i’ll tell you mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="Guide" /><category term="Homecook" /><category term="Homecooking" /><category term="Pudding" /><category term="HealthyFood" /><category term="NepaliFood" /><summary type="html">THE ULTIMATE CROWN OF NEPALI CUISINE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/Kheer.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Week in a Nutshell | August 2019</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/My-Week-In-A-Nutshell/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Week in a Nutshell | August 2019 " /><published>2019-08-23T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-23T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/My-Week-In-A-Nutshell</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/My-Week-In-A-Nutshell/">&lt;p&gt;It’s pretty hard to justify what it is like to be busy as a student when the world assumes you’re not. A student also has
equally busy day, as any other 9 to 5 workers or a house wife or any other people who earn for a living. This busy city life
definitely bores your soul and makes it wonder why you’re even living. In the midst of pollution and population, there are so many
things that you miss to reckon. Things that may have power to move your soul, or the things that could bring a smile to your face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, my morning starts at 5 with a cup of hot lemon with ginger honey. Next thing, I rush out from home to catch a 5:45 bus
to my college. Half the time, i’m asleep on the bus, and most of the time in class. Upon reaching home, I take a nap, go to the gym
and prepare myself for the next day nonchalantly. And if you’re day looks like this, perhaps you forget that there is a world outside,
which can give you enough reasons to feel that the life you’re living might not be that bad as it seems. And so, last Saturday
it clicked in my mind to note those many-few small-big things that made me smile. Today, I bring you a blog based on it.
Mind you, I am extremely sensitive, so even you if you bring me a cup of water, I might cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;On the streets of Basantapur&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While strolling on the streets of Basantapur, a lot of kids try to convince you to buy a bottle of water from them. I was also a part of
their small initiative to sell the water. Two kids randomly came to me and offered me to buy one. I on the other hand always
carry a bottle of water with me. So instead I convinced them that I carry my own bottle. But because they are kids, they kept nagging.
It was quite difficult to escape them as well, one because they were super cute and two, they were kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next thing I did was asked if they were thirsty. They denied at first but later accepted that they were. I offered them the water I had.
They drank it like they were thirsty for a while. When I asked if their thirst was quenched, they happily said yes.
After a little chat with them, I remembered I had peanut butter cookies ordered and received from Pokhara that morning.
I gave them the cookies , they grabbed them all. And why not! They may not have eaten good since who knows how long. 
They took a bite and I waited for their reaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still remember their face when they found it to be really good. It still makes me smile every time I think of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, while writing this, I hope they are having a good time and getting the opportunity to go to school everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Crossing the busy street at Mitrapark&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lack of self awareness has changed the way of Traffic in Kathmandu. If there aren’t any traffic police in every junction, then
there obviously is a hassle of vehicles and pedestrians. In situations as such, I definitely have a hard time crossing roads every single time.
Monday was something similar. I was trying to cross one of the busiest streets of Mitrapark. Few others were easily crossing it. Easily
might not be the appropriate word but for an agyrophobic, they made it look simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept struggling for a while when a man around his sixties came to me and asked if I was scared. I was definitely scared but 
couldn’t admit it properly. Out of nowhere, he asked me if I have watched the classic Bollywood blockbuster Sholay and if I 
remember a dialogue of Mr. Amitabh Bachhan. I had watched the movie time and again but was confused on which dialogue he was
specifically talking about. He reminded me as he went on saying it, “JO DAR GAYA SAMJHO MAR GAYA”. Which if translated to english 
is if you’re scared, you’re dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He acquainted me to the other side of the road and asked me to brave. I hope he is happily living in his sixties. I wish him good health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Struggling with period pain&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think about periods, and that women have an average of 450 periods in their lifetime, I feel really proud of women all around
the globe. Cramps, back pain, mood swings, “never-quick-enough” painkillers, hot water bags and hot showers are
quite on demand and exercise and social plans are off the hook. It’s basically that
time of the month where you pretend to be okay but on the inside, your’e dying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, my pain are the worst ones. In most of the cases they are.
You could even say it a coincidence, but there’s one person in my life, who by the grace of god, has always taken care of me when I feel like ending my world. 
That person has stood in the scorching heat with me when I was looking for warmth in some 29 degree celsius, always managed to rush to the drug store to get me medicines, 
and come back with snacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To that someone, who held me when I fainted multiple times, who brought me hot waters and medicines and snacks that I love,
and who made sure I ate, I hope I can always pay it forward whenever I get the chance to. Also, I wish good luck, prosperity 
and a loyal life partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Deciding to be decisive&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s this weird practice of Nepalese people of believing in astrology and following astrologer’s suggestions. That’s how
last week I also ended up with a so called Astrologer that scans the fingerprints of each finger and prepares a 40 page
documentation on things I have been carrying since birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The so called astrologer is a specialist of Neuro-Linguistic Programming (NLP). If you are new to this then NLP is a scientific 
approach to communication, personal development and psychotherapy. When my official report arrived and I had a private counselling
session, I was told that I have a higher gross motor skills and that is why I cannot say NO to anyone and anything. Also, because of
it I am a confused person and cannot take any decisions because higher the gross motor skills, the more the thoughts are processed which
makes decision making a tough job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a bit of a chat with one of my closest friends about this and what he had to say was, I can completely understand you 
because a part of me knows you better than anything but also because I am somewhat like you. And that’s where he told me that
both of us will work on ourselves and that I will never have to feel alone when struggling on a daily basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I retaliate what he said to me, I think I am very blessed to have someone like him in my life. And also, if he was the one
to share, I might not be able to tell him that both of us will work on it. I hope I can always be available to him whenever he needs
a helping hand.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Smile" /><category term="Journal" /><category term="SelfThoughts" /><category term="Howamifeeling" /><category term="Mentalwellness" /><category term="Selfcare" /><category term="People" /><category term="Solitude" /><category term="Extrovert" /><category term="Intuition" /><category term="Thisweek" /><summary type="html">It’s pretty hard to justify what it is like to be busy as a student when the world assumes you’re not. A student also has equally busy day, as any other 9 to 5 workers or a house wife or any other people who earn for a living. This busy city life definitely bores your soul and makes it wonder why you’re even living. In the midst of pollution and population, there are so many things that you miss to reckon. Things that may have power to move your soul, or the things that could bring a smile to your face.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/smiles.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Kathmandu Food Tour | Local Eateries</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Best-Food-Joints-In-Kathmandu/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kathmandu Food Tour | Local Eateries" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Best-Food-Joints-In-Kathmandu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Best-Food-Joints-In-Kathmandu/">&lt;p&gt;WE LOVE KATHMANDU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite of polluted areas and chaos of the place, it has its own local cuisine with beautiful aspects and a strong grip in the taste of food which has won our hearts . 
And it is very important that you know, where to eat and what to eat.
People involved in satisfying customers with their food try their best to deliver a good taste to the tongue as they are the taste makers. And when
it comes to locals presenting their food in the market, undeniably, they’re the best.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People do like to find places with amazing ambiance and food to chill and eat, but are most often busy and short
of money. So they want foods that are fast and tastes delicious. Often they follow their friend’s recommendation
or food instagrammers but their recommendation can have significant sway over you and where you have your next meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some top local eateries around Kathmandu that you might want to try out if you’re around that street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Khyarloom's Momo&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any Nepali that doubts in momos , are either not Nepali, or  have never tried momos.  Nepalese people
want momos any season in any weather. And Khyarloom’s momo has undoubtedly been able to please their customers since the past 40 years.
Run by locals in the streets of Sukedhara, their momo and their peanut sauce is a match made in heaven. The size of the momo
is big enough for your tummy to be full with eight to ten pieces. Every item you eat costs you at most of 120Rs, with enough
serving size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After you get to Sukedhara Chowk, take the alley beside the Traffic office. A minute of walk leads you to 
Laxmi Bank Chowk. Take right until you reach a three way junction. Take left from the junction and you will find Global Cafe
to your left. On your right, a bit ahead of Global cafe, is where Khyarloom is located.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Khaarlyoom+Momo/@27.7302662,85.3475831,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x9d34963f08104762!8m2!3d27.7302662!4d85.3475831&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;R.S Chinese Food, Naxal&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name might give you a hint about eating typical chinese food, but chinese food in local terms
means eating delicious fast food. R.S Chinese Food at Naxal offers you varieties of fast food starting from fried sausage,
mushroom, tofu, drumstick, meat ball or fresh steamed momos, fried rice, nepali stir fried noodles, burgers and many more
all served with their inhouse special sauce at amazing price with amazing quantity. It is very cheap and tasty at
the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After you reach to Naxal Bhagwati Temple, take the road towards Naxal. This place is about two stores away from the temple.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/R.S+Chinese+Food/@27.7130299,85.3288854,15z/data=!4m2!3m1!1s0x0:0xcc10dbb1dc3441a?sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwiJvcXpzoHkAhWCV30KHYvqABMQ_BIwE3oECA8QCA&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Halal, Dhobidhara Marg &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halal is another local eateries in Kathmandu, that serves you delicious biryani at the cheapest rate. There are several other places that
serves you authentic biryani as well, but they are extremely expensive. And that’s how hunting a place that serves authentic
biryani was important to me. When I finally found the place, I was excited to try my taste. 
They serve a plate for 200Rs only. The spices in their biryani is rich.The sad part is that because the preparation takes time, they only serve
it on Sundays, Tuesdays and Fridays. Personally, for a biryani lover like me, it’s a win win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This place lies in between the alley beside City Center towards Putalisadak.
Take the alley beside City Center towards QFX Kumari. About 500 meters ahead, to your right, you will find this shop, which looks
like a tea shop that has a hoarding board written halal in it. Make sure, you carefully walk the whole way and not miss it. You can even ask the locals around if you get confused.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Halal+Fast+Food/@27.70838,85.3230188,19z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb1907d340e08d:0x972d3cee45263fde!8m2!3d27.7083802!4d85.3235659&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Syanko's Katti Roll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Syanko’s Katti Roll can now be phrased as the “national katti roll”, as their outlet are quite spread all over the valley now, serving us delicious rolls since the past fifteen years. My personal one around Kathmandu lies at two places, one at Sinamangal, which not only offers you delicious
rolls, but also has variety of other fast foods and the other one lies at Baneshwor, whose menu is limited to rolls only. These are the
oldest Syanko’s Rolls at Kathmandu. You should definitely try their double egg double chicken roll. You’ll love it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Syanko’s Rolls are scattered in various places. You can find the store nearby you easily in the maps.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Syanko+Katti+Rolls/@27.6959163,85.3501305,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb1987cb678083:0xa6c118f00289fbb8!8m2!3d27.6959163!4d85.3523192&quot;&gt;Click here to view the location of Sinamangal Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/search?client=ubuntu&amp;amp;hs=x&amp;amp;channel=fs&amp;amp;q=syanko+katti+roll&amp;amp;npsic=0&amp;amp;rflfq=1&amp;amp;rldoc=1&amp;amp;rlha=0&amp;amp;rllag=27693979,85336294,1837&amp;amp;tbm=lcl&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwj4n6vU14HkAhUHYysKHcEhASQQjGp6BAgJEDg#rlfi=hd:;si:18245701401264872526,y,xxdrydO7B5Y;mv:!1m2!1d27.75948537485524!2d85.40147199680007!2m2!1d27.648386262197185!2d85.1834620480696!4m2!1d27.703949958553736!2d85.29246702243483!5i13&quot;&gt;Click here to view other location of Syanko Katti Rolls.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Khawa Kharpo Noodles Factory, Fulbari, Bouddha&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you happen to be around Bouddha, noodles of Khawa Kharpo is a must try. The shop lies at about five minutes walk from
the stupa and serves you the best plate of noodles you’ll ever eat. Like the name itself says “factory”,  the noodles are their in-house
production. They produce the noodles, cook it and serve you fresh right in front of your eyes. It generally opens up after 11 A.M so make
sure you don’t go there for breakfast. White boiled noodles, served with fresh Chinese Spinach with the choice of your toppings(buff or egg)
and their sauce is actually a treat to your taste buds. They also serve another Tibetan dish named “Laphing”, which also is worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;After you get into the gates of Bouddha, make a round from your left until you find an alley. Take that alley, and go straight.
You will soon find out series of laphing joints. After you pass onto chatterbox laphing, you will find the shop in your left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Khawa+Karpo+Tasty+Noodle+Factory/@27.7246606,85.3644082,15z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x0:0x4bc10d04292510d7!8m2!3d27.7246606!4d85.3644082&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;TIP TOP Samosa Pasal, Swachapu Marga&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tip top has undoubtedly been able to win hearts of Nepalese with their samosas and variety of other indian sweets and foods. The reason why
there’s this huge crowd at every outlet of Tip Top is because of their samosas. Samosa is simply mashed potatoes with spices stuffed inside
a flat dough, made into a triangle and deep fried. A piece of samosa at tip top costs you twenty five rupees only and two would
be enough for a hungry stomach. They serve it with their house sauce that’s tangy and sweet at the same time. The samosa goes really
well with the sweet-tangy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tip Top Sweets at Kathmandu is located in several places. There are a total of four outlets in the valley and three of them lies in Kathmandu
whereas the other one lies in Lalitpur.
The authentic samosa pasal of Tip Top however is situated on the road from Bishal Bazar to Indrachowk.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Tip+Top+Samosa+Pasal/@27.7100067,85.308241,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb18fe8e321937:0xfea16a198f4e9a7e!8m2!3d27.710002!4d85.310435&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;NPP Fast Food, Newroad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any fast food lover in Nepal loves what NPP has to offer and specially its their in house sauce that has won hearts ever since.
People here basically love NPP and the variety of stick foods along with their momo. NPP Food Service also has successfully been
able to open various outlets in the valley. You should definitely try out their sausage, potato sticks, tofu and momo if you ever happen
to be there. Another recommendation would be to have their c-momo which is a win win too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you reach to Bishal Bazar at New Road, take your left until you reach a junction. About five minutes walk and you’ll find this amazing food joint 
in your right.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/NPP+Food+Service/@27.7033473,85.3093825,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb191227c506d1:0xc9e97cd54f827cb7!8m2!3d27.7033426!4d85.3115765&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Jhigu Che, Ganeshthan&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jhigu che by far is my top favourite Newari food joints around Kathmandu. Located in the heart of Chabahil, this place
serves you authentic Newari cuisine with best of flavours. A family run local shop has a limited items in their menu but they have
been able to take their creativity to a different level by inventing water momo. Water momo is basically momo made by 
boiling in the water. When we asked how was it possible, the chef explained that it took him almost six months to finally success
into making water boiled momos. They have the tastiest veg choila i.e. soyabean served with mixed spices. This place
is definitely a must visit place if you are around Chabahil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you are at Chabhil chowk then take the alley towards Ganeshthan Temple. About 500 meters straight towards Mitrapark into the alley and
you’ll find this place on your left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Jheegu+Cheen+Newari+Stick+Food/@27.7145755,85.3428871,18z/data=!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb1970677994c1:0x335a4e66dc203180!8m2!3d27.7155027!4d85.3433754&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Burger Freak, Freak Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burgers are my personal favourite and when this place flooded into food blogger’s instagram I had to try it. On visiting the shop, I
was quite amazed to find out the price they had set for every burgers. Trying their special burger is by far the best food
that has ever happened to me. All the burgers range upto 250Rs which is totally satisfying as you are served delicious burger 
with enough fillings. If you ever happen to be around Freak Street, DO NOT MISS this burger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you reach freak street, a bit ahead of Palpasa Cafe, you will find an alley that goes to Snowman cafe. Burger Freak
is about a hundred meters away from snowman’s cafe.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Burger+Freak/@27.7024963,85.3059958,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb193ca6629d3d:0x79e3007e55d2bcd5!8m2!3d27.7024916!4d85.3081898&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Snowman Cafe, Freak Street&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Snowman cafe is one of the oldest cafe of freak street. They have been able to win hearts of their customers since the past
50 years, and literally everyone knows about this place. This is one of those places which has amazing memory of every college 
students. People go here for their cakes and coffees and they are delicious and affordable at the same time. Snowman’s cafe now has a vintage touch since 
the interior hasn’t been changed or renovated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;There’s a small alley that connects freak street to Newroad. Just take the alley and the cafe lies two house away.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Snowman+Cafe/@27.7024711,85.3057156,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb18567c0902ab:0x6953acf71c7af024!8m2!3d27.7024664!4d85.3079096&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Grill Durbar, Sankhamul&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever crave for a big piece of grilled meat,  grill durbar, without a doubt the is the ultimate saviour. Grill durbar
has a variety on the grills starting from normal to extremely spicy. It is loaded with flavours and the spicy sauce
they serve along is to die for. With very reasonable price, though this place doesn’t seem to be a local one,
it is a small shop with large packets of flavours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Location&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;From Baneshowr Chowk, you got to take the road to Sankhamul. You have to go downhill untill you find a turning. Grill durbar is
right at your left when you take the turning to the left.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/place/Grill+Durbar/@27.6844814,85.3315228,17z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m5!3m4!1s0x39eb199ef575be35:0x65ba0ddf1c394dfb!8m2!3d27.6844767!4d85.3337168&quot;&gt;Click here to view location on the map.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several other places that serves you delicious foods at amazing prices. I have only highlighted the places located at
Kathmandu. Soon, I will be writing on local eateries around Lalitpur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What’s your favourite place to eat around the valley? Put them in the comment box. Until next time peace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">WE LOVE KATHMANDU.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/street.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Making of Banana Bread | Home Cooking</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Banana-Bread/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Making of Banana Bread | Home Cooking" /><published>2019-08-14T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-14T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Banana-Bread</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Banana-Bread/">&lt;p&gt;BAKING AT HOME INDEED IS A PLEASURE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dear foodies, I know you have landed on this page after randomly scrolling on several pages,
trying to find that one thing which might actually catch your guards off. Having a healthy diet but also the fact that your 
sweet tooth wants something pleasing as well as interesting at the same time. It’s probably weekend and now you prefer your bed more 
than anything in the world so you decide not to go out. And this is how you wonder if baking is what you want to do. 
Be it the ingredients, equipments or the time, something always has been stopping you from taking a lead, but not anymore. Today, 
I present you a recipe that you’ll probably would stick for your entire life. This recipe involves making a bread which is indeed an art 
of cooking, not everyone can master at. Every baker has at least ten thousand stories to tell until they make a perfect slice of bread. 
I do have my own share of stories. The rest is history! So my friend, if you’ve ever thought of making your piece of bread at home, 
let’s indulge in this recipe. I might have forgotten to mention about banana being the king here, but never mind, let’s make a banana bread today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting thing you might find here is that I do not have an oven at home. Instead it’s the microwave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Baking in the microwave is very tricky as one minute you’ll have the best bread ever, and the other, you’ll have it all
  burned. You really need to be cautious about what’s going on inside the oven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have come up with this recipe after failing numerous times. Sometimes, the batter would get runny, the other times I
would overcook it. Because I do not have an oven and need to use a microwave, it always used to be frustrating when I would try to make it the best and
it would turn out to be inedible. Make sure you bake it with love. That way, you can finally get a
perfect piece of food to eat and enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;recipe-contents&quot;&gt;
 &lt;div class=&quot;ingredients&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ul&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 cup unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;A cup of all purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;A cup of whole wheat flour&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Three completely ripe bananas&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon salt&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon baking soda&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;3 tablespoon sugar&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons of lemon zest&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;A teaspoon of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Two teaspoon cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Three teaspoon honey&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
          
 &lt;div class=&quot;directions&quot;&gt;
   &lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Directions&lt;/h2&gt; 
     &lt;ol&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Butter a medium Bundt pan. In a medium bowl, whisk together flour, salt, cinnamon powder, baking soda, and baking powder.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Mash the bananas using a fork. You can make a runny paste out of it or keep the chunks.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Using an electric mixer, beat the butter, sugar, honey and lemon zest on medium-high until light and fluffy, 3 to 4 minutes. Beat in the mashed bananas, then the eggs, one at a time, scraping down sides of bowl as necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Reduce mixer speed to low. Add half the flour mixture, and then the remaining flour mixture. Mix just until combined (do not overmix).&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Transfer the batter to the prepared pans and microwave until a toothpick inserted in the center comes out clean. Keep checking the batter in every 10 minutes interval. Cool the bread in the pan for 25 minutes, then turn it out onto a wire rack to cool&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;li&gt;Enjoy the bread with your favourite drink.&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;/ol&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;If you tried making this at home, drop a comment below and share about how it ended up. Do not worry if you’re just a beginner.
Failing teaches you how to master it the next time. Also, would love to hear your horror baking stories. Even if the bread turned out 
inedible. The first time I tried this, I burned half the bread. So it’s alright. You’ll have it even better than most famous shops one day.
And if possible, we might even open a shop together. What do you say?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="Food" /><category term="Guide" /><category term="Home Cooking" /><category term="Bakery" /><category term="BananaBread" /><category term="Bread" /><category term="leanin15" /><category term="Healthy Food" /><category term="Gluten Free" /><category term="Baking" /><summary type="html">BAKING AT HOME INDEED IS A PLEASURE.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/bananabreakblurred.webp" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Rara Lake Tour | Travel Blog</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Rara-Lake-Tour/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rara Lake Tour | Travel Blog" /><published>2019-08-10T00:00:00+05:45</published><updated>2019-08-10T00:00:00+05:45</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Rara-Lake-Tour</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Rara-Lake-Tour/">&lt;p&gt;GUIDING YOU TO HEAVEN.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A group of eight friends, some who knew each other very well, while some who had no idea who the rest of them would be, abruptly decided to go on a trip to the far western land of Nepal.
Travelling usually takes a lot of patience, specially when the place you’re about to go has difficult roads, difficult transportation facilities and the most important one: when you’re budget travelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travelling far away with friends as we scramble in the roads, it honestly is a unifying bond that doesn’t discriminate or judge. Packed up and ready from the bus park in Kathmandu, we headed towards Amilia, Dang where a friend of ours awaited with a reserved jeep.
The bus took off at seven in the evening and so did our adrenalin. With lots of stories to share, and extreme junk food packages, the road trip to Amilia ended in a blink of an eye.
Travelling allows you to enjoy to the fullest, warms the depth of your soul and always leaves you curious with what the next minute has to offer. And that’s what we were, young and curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place we were headed was one of the best place Nepal has to offer to you. The place beyond the beautiful horizon and something that was phrased as, “Heaven is a myth. Rara is real”. When I think of it now, I feel as if my journey is a dream that fills
the root of my heart and gives me the feeling of accomplishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rara lake is the biggest freshwater lake in Nepal. Situated in a small district of Nepal, Mugu, surrounded by hills all around at an altitude of 2990m is one of the must visit place in Nepal. Often times people assume that you got to trek to reach there,
but we have several other ways to explore western Nepal and the lake itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/raracontent.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Ways To Travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Airways&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a flight from Kathmandu to Nepalgunj and from Nepalgunj to Talcha Airport. Rara lake is four hour hike away from Talcha airport.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can also take a flight from Nepalgunj to Jumla. From Jumla you need to either take a bus or jeep to Gamagadhi. Gamagadhi is the district headquarters of Mugu. The lake is five hours hike from Gamagadhi.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Roadways&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take a bus to Surkhet or Nepalgunj. You can get a bus to Kalikot which would be a whole day drive. From Kalikot, you got to switch bus to Nagma and from Nagma another bus that leads to Gamagadhi. As mentioned earlier, the lake is five hours hike from Gamagadhi. 
The bus travels along the famous Karnali Highway.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The second and the most flexible and comfortable way would be to reserve a jeep. You do not necessarily need to reserve it from the place you live in. We travelled to Dang by bus and 
reserved a jeep there for five days which cost us around forty five thousand Nepali Rupees for eight people.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Trek&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rara lies in the Karnali region that has amazing landscapes and experience the authentic western past of Nepal from food to people. 
You can find several options in the internet if you look for Khaptak trek that en routes Rara Lake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Travel Like We Did&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Day 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First day of our travel actually started at 7pm in the evening, in the night bus, with friends on the highway to Western Nepal. I personally knew everyone of them, but yes, there were people who hadn’t met each other their entire life.
To be honest, travelling with strangers lets you leave your shit behind and focus only on the wonderful stories to talk about. The challenge this time was not only to explore a different environment but also new people and let your guards down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like mentioned earlier we took a bus from Kathmandu upto Amilia, Dang where a friend of ours was waiting with a reserved jeep and started our road trip.
One of the best part of tripping around west is the fields on Terai, the vibes Bardiya National Park gives in between and the variety of animals you spot in between. We had our lunch in Kohalpur and headed towards Surkhet. And would you even call it a road trip if your tire doesn’t get punctured at least once? Plannings beforehand did let us know that our destination for the day was Manma,
but because punctured tire took time, we started late and reached to Rakham that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Accomodation at Rakam&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pretty much expect good accommodation upto Surkhet but after that you meet people who might even sleep at the floor but give you their bed. Sometimes, it’s the materialistic things people want, but when someone would sacrifice their comfort for yours, that’s when you know, you’ve met a good soul. 
People there do not have much to offer except for what they have and that honestly stands out. At Rakham, you do not find big hotels but you can find enough home with bigger hearts. The one we stayed had a family of five who made us delicious Nepali Thali, with a taste of Karnali, cooked in fire with love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we asked what they would cost for a night, they said we only need to pay for the food and pay what we feel like for the accommodation. We then paid three thousand rupees to the family of the home stay and they gave us warm farewell full of blessings and good luck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Day 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second day started with much excitement than the previous one because the lake awaited us more than anything. Reaching Manma the first day would have made our schedule up to time, but when they say whatever happens, happens for best, they are true. Our next stop for lunch was Nagma. The road to Nagma wasn’t that sophisticated but people we were with taught us to live in the moment and enjoy it. As the roads started getting complex,
friends started getting simpler. And when we finally rested our butts out of the jeep in Nagma, the view we had in front of us was amazing. The barren hills, the over speed flow of river, the sound the water flow was making, at most 10 houses attached with one other, and people with rough red cheeks did let us realize that people do live in such places which had nothing yet everything. The river that flows had the purest freshwater.
The views, the bridges and small architect in them that signifies Kings and Queens were worth the watch. Since we were half day late according to the schedule we had made, so after filling our tummy with yummy food at Nagma we decided that we will not be stopping any way until we reach to our destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At about 6 in the evening we finally entered the Khaptad National Park region where we were suggested not to go further and rather spend the night somewhere
nearby but because we were so determined to see the lake before our eyes first thing in the morning we didn’t stop. At 9:30 pm we reached to Salleri, from where the road ends, and travellers have to hike. The locals there suggested us to stay rather than to hike at night, but our young blood, fueled hormones didn’t let us stop. So finally, in the cold windy shivering weather of Rara, we decided to walk up until we reach to our hotel. I tell you, the hike was worth the effort we had made
until then, worth the equation everyone shares today, and worth the bond that got stronger. When we finally reached our hotel at about past midnight, we were warmly welcomed with hot waters and fresh food. We got our tents and finally slept not knowing what the day after had to offer us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Day 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since waking up to the lake was what everyone of us had in our mind, early morning at Rara had a surprise for us. It snowed for the first time that year, and the view was worth the travel. Google pictures of Rara always had few of them covered with snow, but to see it right in front of your eyes, the process, where slowly all the greens turn into white withing a short span of time is breathtaking. The only thing that was disturbing was the unconditional cold that 
wasn’t going anywhere until the sun showed up. And no matter how much you want the snow, you’ll eventually crave for the sun. The only way to beat the cold weather was to hike around the biggest freshwater lake and few minutes later, the beauty of lake warms you up naturally. We were served delicious breakfast that morning, that had roasted potatoes, omelet, typical nepali chapatis of buckwheat and a warm cup of tea. We spent the rest of the day, in front of the lake, 
admiring its beauty. Few friends of mine, further hiked to Murma Top, which is said to be the view-point of Rara.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Day 4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After having our breakfast the morose thought of leaving this place hit me I did not want to leave. But like the old saying goes, “All good things must come to an end”, it was time to bid farewell to this beautiful place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Rara decided to give us a warm and sunny goodbye. As we sail our boat on the lake the sun and the lake sang the song of colours in unison; The lake was blue, green and yellow all at once. At that particular instant I wanted time to freeze; alas! That was not an option. We left with a heavy heart, and a determined soul to come back sooner than later. We followed the same trail embracing each moment to catch our jeep where we left it a couple of days back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were very lucky to have a good driver who would laugh in our jokes, and add his own wit. We spent our night at Nagma, retaliating entire journey, and reminding oneself that it was going to end soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Day 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Typically, we had to reach to Amilia by hook or by cook that day, which is a 13 hours drive from Nagma, and I personally respect our driver for achieving it. We did breakfast in the same hotel we stayed,
did our lunch in Manma and dinner somewhere after Bardiya National Park. We rushed to Ghorahi, Dang after dinner and at about two in the midnight, we reached there. Two of our friends departed to Kathmandu from their immediately. One who came in the jeep went along with it, and five of us headed towards Butwal. At about four in the morning, we finally got a bus that went Butwal so we took it. The 2am to 4am wait in Ghorahi for the bus is a story for next time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 class=&quot;text-primary&quot;&gt;Overall Expenses&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From KTM to Amilia, Dang : 1400 Rupees (You can get a cheaper fare)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Amilia to Rara and back to Ghorahi : 11000 Rupees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Ghorahi to Butwal : 200 Rupees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From Ghorahi to Kathmandu : 1 Thousand Rupees (You can get a cheaper fare)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name>Aayusha</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">GUIDING YOU TO HEAVEN.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/rara.webp" /></entry></feed>